Guide to the Hemingway Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hemingway family papers
1830-1961
MS 276
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
The papers consist of correspondence, financial papers, and memorabilia of the Hemingway and Hart families.
Hemingway family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of S. B. Hemingway estate, 1963.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Samuel Burdett Hemingway, 1886-1958: educator; A.B., Yale 1904, A.M., 1905, Ph.D., 1908; instructor in English, Yale 1908-1913, asst. prof., 1913-1926, assoc. prof., 1926-1933, prof. English, 1933-1950, prof. emeritus, 1950-1958; master of Berkeley College, 1937-1950, Master emeritus, 1950-1958.
For charts outlining the genealogical relations of the Hemingway and Dimock families, please consult the Genealogical Charts.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, financial papers, and memorabilia of the Hemingway and Hart families.
Families; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945; Europe -- Description and travel; Europe; New Haven (Conn.); Educators; Hemingway, Mary Jordon Dimock; Hemingway, Samuel Burdett, 1883-1958; Hart family; Hemingway family; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - 1896-1920 (Box 1)
    - 1921-1938 (Box 2)
    - 1939-1943 (Box 3)
    - 1944-1949 (Box 4)
    - 1950-1961 (Box 5)
  - Hart family correspondence, Hemingway estate papers and financial records, 1830-1950 (Box 6)
    - Oversized letter of Burdett Hart to Asa N. Hart, 1844 June 1 (Box 10)
  - Financial records and memorabilia, 1895, 1900s, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Berkeley College students, 1937-1950 (Box 8)
  - Two notebooks on "Co. B, A.S.T.P.R.", 1940s (Box 8)
  - Two notebooks of Mary (Dimock) Hemingway, 1902, 1904 (Box 8)
  - Notes on cash outlays, undated (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1930s, undated (Box 8)
  - Notebooks on Berkeley College students (restricted), 1937-1950 (Box 9)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The notebooks in Box 9, concerning Berkeley College students, are restricted until 2028 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.